https://www.formsite.com/privacy/

Privacy Policy Statement
Your privacy is important to us. Whether you are a Formsite customer or a form visitor, your information represents your trust in our organization and this page is intended to help you understand what we collect and what we do with it.
Contents:
Information we collect
Formsite customersForm visitors
How we use your information
Third party disclosureOnward TransferFormsite customersForm visitors
Your personal data
Access to personal dataLimiting the use and disclosure of your personal dataPersonal data submitted through forms
CCPA
Formsite customersForm visitorsData access and deletion requests
GDPR
Inquiries & complaints
Legal disclosure
Information we collect
Formsite customers
When you sign up for a Formsite account, you give us some personal information like your email address. If you choose to authorize your account using one of our integrated login types like Facebook or Google, your email address is retained for authentication purposes.
If you choose to pay for a service upgrade using a credit card, we collect your name, billing address, and credit card information. If you email us, your email address and any personal information is contained and archived.
We use commonly-used internet technologies like cookies and Google Analytics to track and analyze site visitors and customer interactions.
Your Formsite account activities and IP address are logged when you are logged-in to your account, as are many of your actions related to form building, results processing, and other services provided inside your account.
Form visitors
Formsite form visitors who complete forms made by our customers and may, depending entirely on the customers’ forms, divulge personal information and/or manually uploaded files, are collected and stored within our secure database and file storage areas.
We use commonly-used internet technologies like cookies and Google Analytics to track and analyze site visitors and customer interactions. Form visitor logs are kept to track site usage, statistical information on technical capabilities and version numbers, and behavioral tracking. No Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is recorded through these technologies.
How we use your information
Third party disclosure
We may disclose your personal information to these types of third parties for the purposes described in this privacy policy (for purposes of this section, “you” and “your” refer to both customers and visitors unless otherwise indicated):
Our service providers: We may share your information with service providers who help us provide and support our services and other business-related functions. Examples are hosting data, payment processing, performance analytics, technical support, and third-party agencies helping to enhance our service offerings. These third parties are contracted to use any personal information in a manner consistent with this privacy policy.Third party authentication: We may share your information when requested by you as an account creation or login authentication, for example, through Google or Facebook, or as an integration authentication, for example, through Google, Salesforce, Microsoft, or any of the other integration services.Advertising partners: We may use third party advertising services that collect personal information about usage, location, and demographics for the purpose of analysis and management for our advertising. We do not sell or provide any data from form results. We use cookies and other tracking techniques like pixels and linked scripts to collect information about usage to enhance our features and target our advertising.Legal: Legitimate law enforcement, regulatory, government, court, or other third party as a result of a lawful request or order, or to protect you or us from fraud.Future business partners: In the event of a sale, reorganization, acquisition, or other transfer of ownership, any third party agent will be subject to this privacy policy.
Onward Transfer
Formsite complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for onward transfers of personal data from the EU, the UK, and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.
Formsite customers
Formsite uses your information as part of your requested services as a Formsite user. For example, if you have elected to use one of our integrated login types like Facebook or Google to authenticate your login, your saved information will be used to authorize your login.
Formsite may send you email messages on a regular basis to keep you apprised of your membership status, and inform you of new products and services, newsletters, and other marketing materials. If you wish to unsubscribe from the emails, you can click the Unsubscribe link at the bottom or deselect the ‘Keep me updated’ setting on your “User menu->Profile” page.
We may use your information to improve our web site, services, and advertising. Formsite does not sell, share, rent, or trade any information, including your email address and any information from integrated login types like Facebook or Google, with third parties for their promotional purposes. We may share information collected with third parties that work on our behalf for service improvement and analysis, or as may be required by law.
Form visitors
Formsite does not access, view, sell, share, rent, or trade any information collected by customer forms for any purposes aside from naturally occurring exposure as a result of customer support, fraud prevention, or other maintenance activities, or as may be required by law.
Your personal data
Access to personal data
You have the right under Privacy Shield to access, correct or delete your personal data. To inquire about your personal data, you can contact us via https://www.formsite.com/contact/.
Limiting the use and disclosure of your personal data
Formsite customers can manage the account and profile settings within the account, or you may contact us for assistance directly by submitting the form at https://www.formsite.com/contact/. You can also manage information collected through the form results through the Formsite account to assist you with responding to requests to access, correct, update or delete information that you receive from your forms.
Additionally, EU, Swiss, and UK residents can object to processing of their personal information, ask to restrict processing of their personal information or request portability of their personal information. You can exercise these rights by contacting us from https://www.formsite.com/contact/.
We respond to all requests from those wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection law. We may ask you to verify your identity in order to help us respond efficiently to your request. If we receive a request from a form visitor, we will either respond directly to their request or forward them to the account owner for assistance.
Personal data submitted through forms
Formsite does not own, control or direct the use of any of the customer data stored or processed by a customer or user via the Service. Only the customer or users are entitled to access, retrieve and direct the use of such customer data. Formsite is largely unaware of what customer data is actually being stored or made available by a customer or user to the Service and does not directly access such customer data except as authorized by the customer, or as necessary to provide Services to the customer and its users.
Formsite is not responsible for the content of the personal data contained in the customer data or other information stored on its servers (or its subcontractors’ servers) at the discretion of the customer or user nor is Formsite responsible for the manner in which the customer or user collects, handles disclosure, distributes or otherwise processes such information.
All information collected by Formsite forms is securely collected, stored, and owned by the Formsite account owner. Access to the data is authorized by the username(s) and password(s) for that account. Formsite provides sufficient and reasonable protection for personal information against unauthorized access, loss, or misuse.
CCPA
The California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) adds protections for residents in California by requiring businesses to allow access to data containing personal information. Formsite takes security and privacy seriously and therefore complies completely with the CCPA.
The full text of the CCPA can be found at https://oag.ca.gov/privacy/ccpa and secures privacy rights for California consumers including the right to know what information is collected and how it’s used and shared, the right to delete personal information (with some exceptions), and the right to opt out of the sale of their personal information.
Formsite customers
Formsite’s customers are account owners and the only information we collect is that which is necessary to establish account ownership, i.e., contact information and billing information. As stated in this Privacy policy, Formsite never sells or otherwise shares customer or form data with anyone except where required upon lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
As Formsite has never and will never sell any information about customers or data collected by customer forms, the need for opting out is purely rhetorical. As the CCPA provides for the right to opt out, however, we fulfill that right here: Click here to opt out.
Form visitors
Formsite does not access, view, sell, share, rent, or trade any information collected by customer forms for any purposes aside from naturally occurring exposure as a result of customer support, fraud prevention, or other maintenance activities, or as may be required by law. We provide our customers with the means to be CCPA compliant, but any individual requests need to be directed to the account owners.
Data access and deletion requests
The CCPA establishes rights to consumers in California to access and delete data possessed by an organization. Formsite customers can contact the support staff for these requests.
Form visitors must contact the Formsite account owner with CCPA requests regarding their information. We provide Formsite account owners with tools to quickly search, export, and delete data to support CCPA requests.
Contact us via https://www.formsite.com/contact with any questions or requests.
GDPR
Formsite customers and form visitors from EU, the UK, and Switzerland are protected by the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/679, hereinafter “GDPR”), the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, and the Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Formsite complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks (Privacy Shield) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union, the United Kingdom, and Switzerland to the United States in reliance on Privacy Shield. Formsite has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such information. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/.
Formsite’s adherence to the Privacy Shield policies are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the United States Federal Trade Commission. Formsite is potentially liable in cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU, UK, or Swiss individuals received pursuant to the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield, respectively.
Inquiries & Complaints
In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Formsite commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU, UK, and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should contact our customer support staff at https://www.formsite.com/contact and will be replied to within 45 days.
Formsite has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU, UK, and Switzerland. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact the EU DPAs and the Swiss FDPIC for more information or to file a complaint. The services of EU DPAs and the Swiss FDPIC are provided at no cost to you.
Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website, you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted
Because Formsite does not collect or determine the use of any personal data contained in the customer data and because it does not determine the purposes for which such personal data is collected, the means of collecting such personal data, or the uses of such personal data, Formsite is not acting in the capacity of data controller in terms of the GDPR and does not have the associated responsibilities under the GDPR. Formsite should be considered only as a processor on behalf of its customers and users as to any customer data containing personal data that is subject to the requirements of the GDPR. Except as provided in this Privacy Policy, Formsite does not independently cause customer data containing personal data stored in connection with the Services to be transferred or otherwise made available to third parties, except to third party subcontractors who may process such data on behalf of Formsite in connection with Formsite’s provision of Services to customers. Such actions are performed or authorized only by the applicable customer or user.
The customer or the user is the data controller under the Regulation for any customer data containing personal data, meaning that such party controls the manner such personal data is collected and used as well as the determination of the purposes and means of the processing of such personal data.
Due to the nature of our service, EU, UK, and Swiss form visitors requesting access to or limiting access to their personal information are required to provide the form link, notification email, and/or any other information needed to identify the Formsite account owner, at which time we will refer your request to that customer and will support them as needed to respond to your request.
Legal disclosure
Formsite may be required to disclose personal information to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
Billions of forms submitted
Sign up free
Terms & Conditions
Privacy
About Us
Careers
Blog
Documentation
© 1998-2020 Formsite. All rights reserved.
